Guide to the Angela Davis trial, 1972-1974 M0308
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Angela Davis trial
1972-1974
M0308
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
4.0 Linear feet
Timothy, Mary
Scope and Content
Trial transcripts, tape recordings of impressions of the daily trial proceedings, articles and newsclippings about the trial and Ms. Davis, photographs of the jury, and letters received by Mary Timothy. The material covers the period of the trial (January - June 1972) and the post-trial period, which includes articles published primarily in 1972 as well as Mary Timothy's own account of the trial and the jury system, JURY WOMAN.
Biographical Note
Mary Timothy was foreperson of the 1972 Angela Davis trial jury.
Provenance
Gift of Ellen Timothy, 1979.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
- Trial transcript:, Jan 10 1972 - March 17 1972 (Carton 1)
- Trial transcript:, March 27 1972 - April 27 1972 (Carton 2)
- Trial transcript:, May 1 1972 - June 1 1972 (Carton 3)
- Trial notes:, 3 small notepads and ca. 100 3 x 5 typed cards. (Carton  4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (Miscellaneous to Mrs. Timothy) (Carton  4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Hate mail (Carton  4, Folder 3)
- Big Times interview (unedited) (Carton  4, Folder 4)
- Two xerox copies of Jury Woman ms. (Carton  4, Folder 5)
- Timothy, Mary (Carton  4, Folder 6)
  - Jury Woman
  - Palo Alto, CA, Emty Press, 1974.
- Photographs (Carton  4, Folder 7)
- Typed ms (carbon copy) Mrs. Drumgo (Fleeta Drumgo's mother) (Carton  4, Folder 8)
  - Interview with Ralph DeLange - a juror during the Angela Davis trial Xerox. In Guild by Association, National Lawyers' Guild, Santa Clara Valley Chapter, (3 copies).
- 1. Frame up The opening defense statement made by Angela Y. Davis., March 27, 1972. (Carton  4, Folder 9)
- 2. Peace, Friendship, solidarity Angela Davis in the GDR.
- 3. A political biography of Angela Davis.
- 4. Freed by the people, 1972 Aug 7; 38 pp by National United Committee to free Angela Davis.
- 5. Stop the Grand Jury, Undated; 4 pp.
- 6. Form letter from National Alliance against racist and political repression., 1974 Jan 7; 11 pp.
- 7. Black Workers and the class struggle by Roscoe Proctor, New York, New Outlook Publications, 1972 Feb; 37 pp.
- 1. Angela Davis talks about her future and her freedom in Jet pg. 54-57., 1972 Jul 27 (Carton  4, Folder 10)
- 2. Death in the van in Newsweek, pg 33-34., 1972 Apr 17
- 3. The Angela Davis case: behind the verdict in Newsweek, pg.30., 1972 Jun 19
- 4. Angela's triumphant acquittal in Time, pg 18., 1972 Jun 12
- 5. From the jury box book review of Juror number four by Edwin Kennebeck in Newsweek pg. 84., 1973 Feb 26
- 6. Crime and Justice from The Stanford Observor by Anthony G. Amsterdam, 1972 Aug.; 3 pp.
- 7. The IQ Bias BAttle by Jim Wood in San Francisco Sunday Chronicle., 1972 Sep 24
- 8. Whither thou goest by Ron Rosenbaum in Esquire., nd July
- 9. Angela Davis, from Birmingham to San JOse by Frank Stella in Fusion, pg. 24-25., 1972 July
- 10. Experiments behind bars: doctors, drug companies, and prisoners by Jessica Mitford in The Atlantic., 1973 Jan
- Newsclippings - Trial and aftermath and related incidents. (Carton  4, Folder 11)
- Newsclippings - Trial and aftermath and related incidents. (Carton  4, Folder 12 - 28)
- Audio Tapes
  Note
  Tapes 4a, 4b, and 11, do not seem to be related to the trial, but are medical education recordings.
  - Alternate Juror, March 16, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 1)
  - Jury Selection, March 21, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 2)
  - March 28, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 3)
  - Testimony, Wednesday, April 5 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 5)
  - Monday, April 10, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 6)
  - April 14-19,1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 7)
  - April 20-May 4, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 8)
  - May 12, 1972 (Box  5, Audiocassette 9)
  - May 22, 1972 (First day of defense) (Box  5, Audiocassette 10)
  - Mary Timothy, author of "Jury Woman," interviewed on Art Finley Show, KGO Radio, SF, 1/2/75, 01/2/1975 (Box  5, Audiocassette 12)
    There are six copies of Tape 12 in the box.
  - Library Speech, Mary Timothy, Palo Alto [no date] (Box  5, Audiocassette 13)